- [Joe] As a C# developer, you might be wondering
what's with all the excitement about Python?
C# is, of course, a very popular and capable language.
And it's been around for quite some time now.
But Pythons rise as a favorite language
among programmers has happened along with
the industry's shift to embrace open source
and cloud based computing.
Along with evermore powerful computers
that can execute interpreted languages
like Python faster than ever before.
Hi, I'm Joe Marini.
And I've been building software professionally
for some of the biggest companies in Silicon Valley
for more than 30 years.
I've used a lot of programming languages
throughout my career, including both C# and Python.
And each one of them has their strengths
along with their quirks.
In this course, we'll learn about some of the basics
of the Python language and how it compares to C#.
Then we'll see how various features of C#
are implemented in Python, such as the different ways
you can define and use functions,
implement various aspects of object oriented programming
such as defining classes, implementing interfaces,
and abstract classes.
And make use of the Python collection types
like lists and dictionaries
and see how they compare to their C# versions.
We'll also examine some features that are uniquely Python,
such as magic object methods
and the built-in language functions
that make common data handling operations easy.
Python is a great language to add
to your skillset alongside C#.
So, let's get started.