- [Instructor] There are some concepts
that you should already be familiar with
before you start this course.
So let's take a few moments and review what basic knowledge
you should already have.
First, I'm going to assume
that you're already comfortable in programming with C#
and that you are familiar with
some basic programming principles
and common programming structures like loops
and functions and classes and so on.
After all, this is a course about Python
for existing C# developers,
so I think it's fair to expect
that you're already a knowledgeable C# developer.
I'm also going to assume that you are familiar with
using IDE to build programs such as Visual Studio Code.
I'm going to be using Visual Studio Code in this course,
since it's free and it runs on all major platforms
like Mac, Windows, and Linux,
and it has really great support for both C# and Python.
If you want to learn more about using Visual Studio
to write Python code,
then I suggest watching "Visual Studio Code for Python."
Other than that, you don't really need to know much else.
I'm not going to assume
that you have any prior knowledge of Python, but if you do,
then the course will be that much easier for you.
Assuming that you're okay with these expectations,
then you are ready to continue with the course.