- [Instructor] In order to complete this course,
you'll need to have both .NET
with C# and Python installed on your computer.
So let's start with the C# requirements.
If you don't already have .NET installed,
then in your browser,
go to .net.microsoft.com
and then click on the download button.
Now, if this screen looks different when you visit,
then you can always do a web search for .NET install
and go from there.
So here on the download page,
the version for your operating system
should already be selected.
You want to make sure
that you download the SDK version of .NET
so that you can both build and run your apps.
Don't just download the runtime version of .NET.
So for Windows, what I'm going to choose is .NET SDK,
which is let's see, it looks like it's right here,
the .NET Core SDK.
And by the way, on Windows, choose .Net Core.
You don't need to choose .NET Framework,
that's for building like Windows apps and so on.
We're only going to be building console apps.
So just download the .NET Core SDK.
And then if you're on Linux,
you're going to install .NET Core.
That's this guy right here.
And then finally on Mac iOS,
once again, you're going to choose the .NET Core SDK.
So alternatively,
if you're using a Windows or a Mac, and not Linux,
then you can choose
to download the full Visual Studio itself.
And that will also install the runtime
and the SDKs that you need.
So once you've downloaded and run the .NET installer,
you're going to want to open a terminal window,
and I'm using PowerShell,
and you're going to type the command dotnet --version.
And this should give you a version number
of the .NET framework.
Now, if this command results in an error,
then something went wrong with the installation,
and you'll need to do that again.
Otherwise you should see a version number like this.
You can see I'm using .NET Core 3.1.402.
After you've installed .NET, you can install Python again,
if you don't already have it.
So what you'll do is go to python.org
and then you'll click on Downloads,
and then follow the instructions for your platform.
And again, your platform should already be selected,
but you can manually choose the right platform
if you need to.
And for this course,
it's not necessary to install anything later than 3.8.
So if you've got 3.8 installed on your system,
you should be fine.
You can see that as of this recording, 3.9 is the latest,
but as long as you have 3.8 plus, that's fine.
And then once again, once you've installed,
let's go back to the terminal window,
and we're going to make sure that that worked.
So we're going to type python.
On Mac and Linux,
you might need to type python3,
because those systems still ship
with Python2 installed sometimes.
So make sure that you're running Python version three.
Here on Windows, it's just the command python.
Type python --version.
And you can see that I'm running 3.8.
And then finally,
if you've decided to use Visual Studio Code,
and you need to install it,
then go to code.visualstudio.com.
And again, just install the app for your platform.
Once you've installed it, go ahead and open the app.
And I've got the app open here,
and click on the icon for Visual Studio Code extensions,
which is the small icon here on the bottom.
It shows all these squares coming together.
So if we click on that one,
you'll see the installed extensions,
and you can see I've got C# and Python extensions
already installed.
Both of these are made and supported by Microsoft.
These extensions will give you
some really great language support features,
such as syntax highlighting
and IntelliSense, debugging support,
and a whole lot more.
Now, if you need to install these,
then what you'll do is in the search box up here,
you'll type C#,
and typically it's the first one that comes up,
and you can see it's made by Microsoft,
that's the one you want.
So go ahead and install that one.
And then when that's finished,
you're going to go ahead
and you're going to search for Python.
And once again, that's usually the first one at the top.
You can see it's got, you know, as of this recording,
almost 27 million downloads, again, made by Microsoft.
And this is the one you want to install.
Now you might need to reload VS Code after installing.
So if you see a little blue reload button
next to the extension name,
then go ahead and do it after you install.
All right.
So after you've installed Python.net and VS Code
and the extensions, then you're ready to proceed.