- [Instructor] If you're already
an experienced C# developer,
you might be wondering,
what's so special about Python and why learn it?
After all C# and .NET are pretty popular
and have been around for quite some time now,
so why bother learning a new language?
I think there's several great reasons to do so.
First Python programming is very productive and efficient,
especially if you're prototyping something
and you want to try out an idea quickly,
But that doesn't mean you can't do real work with it.
Python is very popular among some fields,
such as data science, financial modeling,
cloud software development, building command line tools,
and a lot more.
Python is also very flexible.
It supports object oriented programming,
so you can use it that way,
or you can just write procedural code
and not worry too much about using objects.
It's up to you.
There's a huge ecosystem built up around Python now.
There are 100s of pre-built code modules
that you can use in your projects,
both built into the standard library,
as well as available from third parties.
Python forms the foundation
of programming for some very popular products
like the Raspberry Pi or the Django web framework,
just to name a couple.
Python runs almost everywhere.
Just about every major operating system supports it,
such as Windows, Mac, and Linux.
So you can run your programs just about on any device
that has a processor.
All right, let's take a high-level look
at C# compared to Python.
So C# is a statically typed language
with some support for dynamic typing,
whereas Python is a dynamically typed language.
C# code is compiled and built into an app
before it is run.
Python doesn't have this step.
The code is just interpreted as it is executed.
This makes Python a little bit slower than C#,
but it makes the process of development
very quick and simple.
The C# language has grown over time
to be very rich and expressive.
There are all kinds of language constructs
to solve a wide variety of programming problems.
Python tends to focus more on simplicity
and doesn't have a lot of the bells and whistles
that languages like C# has.
Historically C# has been used by enterprise
and Azure developers
along with in-house development
for projects like Windows Forms.
Python has found acceptance among data scientists,
server side cloud developers, and hobbyists.
Now both languages of course
have large passionate user bases
and after spending some time with Python yourself,
you're probably going to understand why that is.